Faith Berry Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: NAACP Task Force on Africa, 1963-1979 (Box I:2-6)
  - Subject files
    - Material sent by or about task force members
      - Graves, Earl, 1977
      - Gregory, Karl D., 1971-1977 (Box I:5)
      - Williams, Franklin, 1974-1976
      - Wilson, Margaret Bush, material on the African-American Conference in Lesotho, 1976
    - Media in Africa
      - Abstract for study, 1976
      - Background information, 1971-1977, undated, (2 folders)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1976-1977
      - Recommendations to the NAACP, undated
    - Namibia, 1974-1976
    - Organization of African Unity, 1977, undated
    - Rhodesia (Zimbabwe)
      - American mercenaries
        - "Americans in the Rhodesian Defense Forces," addendum to task force report, 1977
        - Miscellaneous notes and photocopies, United States citizenship and expatriation laws, 1963-1977, undated
        - Newspaper clippings, 1976-1977
        - Official brochures, information sheets, and application forms, 1976, undated
      - Government publications
        - Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1975-1976
        - Ministry of Information, Immigration and Tourism, 1976-1977
        - Miscellaneous departments, 1976-1977, undated (Box I:6)
      - Rhodesian Catholic Commission for Justice and Peace, 1976
    - Rhodesian Christian Group, 1976
    - Tilcor (Tribal Trust Land Development Corp.), 1970-1977
    - United African National Council, 1976-1977, undated
    - Zimbabwe African National Union (ZANU), Zimbabwe News, Jan.-Feb. 1977
    - Zimbabwe United People's Organization, undated
    - Tanzania
      - Background information, 1967-1977, undated
      - Media
        - General, 1976
        - Notes from interview with Isaac Sepetu, minister for information and broadcasting, 1977
    - United States foreign policy concerning Africa
      - Memorandum on Henry Kissinger's policies toward Angola and southern Africa, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1976-1978
      - Newspaper clippings, 1971-1978
    - Young, Andrew, newspaper clippings, 1977
  - Zambia
    - Government publications, 1968-1976
    - Media, 1974-1977
- Part I: Women's Issues, 1972-1983 (Box I:7-16)
  Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, invoices, reports, speeches, press releases, brochures, printed matter, and newspaper clippings relating to Berry's work with the President's Advisory Committee for Women and the Department of Labor Women's Bureau; her attendance at the United Nations Decade for Women Mid-Decade Conference, the Second International Seminar of the National Council of Negro Women, and the Transcentury Women-to-Women Program; and her research on women's issues between 1977 and 1983.
  Arranged largely sequentially according to activity and alphabetically therein by topic. Miscellaneous subject files comprise the final grouping.
  - President's Advisory Committee for Women (Box I:7)
    - Administrative notebook (arranged as compiled)
      - Table of contents and statement of purpose, undated
      - July 1979 meeting, goals, objectives, motions, and list of women's organizations, 1979, undated
      - History of federal committees and task forces on women, 1972-1977, undated
      - Committee members, biographical information, 1980, undated
        - Staff members, biographical information, 1980, undated
        - Interdepartmental Task Force on Women, 1979
        - Administrative matters, including travel, incentive package, and data management, 1979
        - Congress, ninety-sixth, list of members, undated
      - International Women's Year, membership lists for national commission, continuing committee, and secretariat staff, 1978
      - Labor Department Women's Bureau staff resource list, undated
      - Memoranda, 1979, undated
      - Position description for media coordinator, undated
      - Status of women commissions, committees, and councils, 1978
      - United Nations Decade for Women Mid-Decade Conference, 1979
    - Bibliographies, 1978-1979
    - Brochure and newsletter, 1979
    - Calendar of events, 1979-1980
    - Correspondence, 1979-1980, (2 folders)
    - Day care information, 1979-1980
    - Equal Rights Amendment
      - General, 1976-1979, undated
      - Memoranda concerning briefing on 24 Oct. 1979
      - Report to the President of the United States, 18 Dec. 1979
    - Health issues, 1978-1979 (Box I:8)
    - Issues notebook (incomplete), 1979
    - Memoranda, 1979-1980
    - Newspaper clippings, 1979
    - Outside meetings attended, 1979
    - Poster project, "Help Wanted," 1980
      - Layout design See Oversize
      - Memoranda and drafts
    - Projects completed, 1979-1980
    - Raleigh, N.C., meeting, Sept. 1979
    - White House Conference on Families, 1979-1980
    - Women's organizations, unpublished in-house directory, 1979-1980
      - Alphabetical arrangement of organizations
        - A-U, (5 folders)
        - W-Z, (1 folder) (Box I:9)
      - Media
  - Labor Department Women's Bureau
    - Herman, Alexis M.
      - Biographical information and photograph, 1977-1980, undated
      - Speeches by Herman, 1977-1980, (2 folders)
      - Speeches for Herman
        - Background material, 1979-1980
        - Drafts, 1980
        - Memoranda, 1980
    - Invoices and vouchers, 1980
    - Memoranda and proposals, 1979-1981
    - Press and media projects, 1979-1980
    - Resource Center for Women, Labor Department library project, 1979-1980, undated, (2 folders)
    - Sixtieth Anniversary Conference, "Forward/Adelante: Women and Work in the 80s," Sept. 1980, (2 folders)
  - United Nations Decade for Women Mid-Decade Conference (Box I:10)
    - Conference files
      - Brochures, pamphlets, press releases, and flyers, 1980
      - Newspaper clippings, 1980
      - Non-Governmental Organizations (NGO) Forum
        - Notes on NGO sessions attended, 1980
        - Programs, schedules, and general information, 1980
      - Poster, 1980 See Oversize
      - Press releases, 1980
      - Programs and agenda for meetings, 29-30 July 1980
      - Report to General Assembly, drafts, 1980
        - Chapter 1, "Programme of Action for the Second Half of the United Nations Decade for Women: Resolutions and Discussions"
        - Chapter 5, "Reports of Subsidiary Bodies and Action on These Reports by the Conference"
          - Committee of the whole
          - First committee
          - Second committee
        - Credentials committee
        - Resolution drafts
        - "Review and Evaluation of Progress Achieved in the implementation of the World Plan of Action: Employment"
        - World Plan of Action (summarized version), 1976
    - Miscellaneous printed matter acquired at conference
      - Women's issues (organized by topic)
        - Arts, 1979-1980, undated
        - Communications and publishing, 1980-1981, undated
        - Education, 1980, undated
        - Feminism, 1978-1980, undated
        - Health, reproduction, and child care, 1979-1980, undated, (1 folder)
        - Health, reproduction, and child care, 1979-1980, undated, (1 folder) (Box I:11)
        - International issues (peace, ecology, human rights, and global corporations), 1976-1980, undated
        - Politics, 1979, undated
        - Violence, 1980
        - Work, economy, and income, 1977-1980, undated
      - Women's organizations and information on the status of women (arranged by country or region)
        - Afghanistan, Africa, Afro-Asia, Asia, and Australia
        - Belgium and Bulgaria (Box I:12)
        - Canada, Caribbean, and Chile
        - Denmark
        - France and Great Britain
        - Iran, Iraq, Ireland, Israel, Jamaica, Japan, and Kenya
        - Lebanon, Libya, Netherlands, Nicaragua, and Norway
        - Palestine and Philippines
        - Scandinavia, Senegal, Somalia, South Africa, Sweden, and Switzerland
        - Turkey, USSR, and Zambia
        - United States
          - Delegates to the conference and NGO Forum, 1980
          - Status of women, 1977-1980, (2 folders)
    - National Council of Negro Women, Second International Seminar, Copenhagen, Denmark, 14-24 July 1980
    - Transcentury Women-to-Women Program
      - Itineraries, memoranda, and notes, 1980
      - Morocco, status of women, 1978-1979, undated
      - National Council of Negro Women, 1979-1980
  - Subject files (Box I:13)
    - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act (CETA), 1977-1979
    - Conferences (arranged chronologically)
      - 1977, Nov., National Women's Conference, Houston, Tex.
        - Black women's action plan, 1977
        - National plan of action, 1977
        - Official report, 1977
        - Program and conference follow-up reports, 1977-1979
      - 1978, June, Girls Clubs of America National Seminar, "Today's Girls: Tomorrow's Women," Racine, Wis.
      - 1979
        - May, Women's Work Force Network Conference, Washington, D.C.
        - Sept., National Hook-Up of Black Women Conference, Washington, D.C.
        - Nov.
          - National Council of Negro Women, thirty-ninth national convention, Washington, D.C.
            - Notes and memoranda, 1979-1980
            - Printed matter, 1979, undated
            - Programs and workbook, 1979
          - Continuing Committee of the National Women's Conference, summit meeting, Washington, D.C.
        - Dec., United Methodist ERA Support Project, "A Consultation: Ethnic Minority Involvement for the Equal Rights Movement," Washington, D.C., 1979-1980
      - 1980
        - Jan.-Mar., ERAmerica, meetings of minority organizations and individuals, Washington, D.C.
        - Apr., International Feminist Workshop, Stony Point, N.Y.
        - May, National Council of Negro Women, strategy planning sessions on "Women of Color and ERA," Washington, D.C.
      - 1981, Apr., NAACP Women's Conference, Cincinnati, Ohio
      - 1982, Sept., Institute for Advancement of the Black Female in Corporate Leadership Positions, Howard University, Washington, D.C. (Box I:14)
      - 1983
        - Aug., District of Columbia Commission for Women, Women's Equality Day and "The Role of Black Women in the Struggle for Women's Rights," Washington, D.C.
        - Nov., The Role of Black Women in the Civil Rights Struggle and Beyond: A Consultation, sponsored by the Friends of Margaret Bush Wilson, Washington, D.C.
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1983-1984
          - Drafts of agenda, lists of participants, press releases, notes, and invoices, 1983
          - Papers and speeches, 1983
          - Wilson, Margaret Bush, biographical information, newspaper clippings, leaflets, 1983
    - Education and women's studies programs, 1980-1981
    - Equal Rights Amendment
      - Facts and data, 1972-1980
      - Newspaper and magazine articles, 1979-1983
      - Pamphlets, brochures, and flyers, 1978, undated
      - Poster, United Methodist Family Life Committee, 1978 See Oversize
    - Legislation, budget, and policy, 1980
    - Mary McLeod Bethune Council House, Washington, D.C., 1980-1982
    - Military and women
      - Background material, 1979-1980
      - Newspaper clippings, 1980-1983
      - Notes, undated
      - Women's Equity Action League (WEAL), "Women and the Military," 1979
    - Minority women and equity issues
      - African-American women
        - Equal Rights Amendment, 1976-1980
        - Historical studies, 1975, undated
        - Lists of resources, undated
        - Voting patterns, 1978-1980, undated
      - Asian and Pacific-American women, 1979-1980, undated (Box I:15)
      - Employment, 1975-1980, undated
      - Hernandez, Aileen, and National Organization for Women, 1974-1979
      - Hispanic-American women, 1977-1980, undated
      - Native-American women, 1976-1980, undated
      - Sexism and racism, 1977-1980
    - Social Security
      - Background information, 1979-1983, undated
      - Testimony by Lynda Johnson Robb before House of Representatives Select Committee on Aging, 1979
    - Women's organizations and publications, printed ephemera, 1978-1982, undated
      - A-N, (6 folders)
      - O-W, (4 folders) (Box I:16)
- Part I: Kissinger in Retrospect, 1977 (Box I:16)
  Working script for a documentary program written and produced by Berry for WETA/TV-FM public television in Washington, D.C.
  - Working script, 1977, (6 folders)
- Part I: Oversize, 1978-1982 (Box I:OV 1)
  Posters and a printed resolution.
  Arranged and described according to the series, boxes, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Langston Hughes, 1859-1984 (Box I:OV 1)
    - District of Columbia City Council resolutions
      - Langston Hughes Recognition Resolution, 23 Feb. 1982
        - Printed resolution, 1982 (Container 1)
  - Women's Issues, 1972-1983
    - President's Advisory Committee for Women
      - Poster project, "Help Wanted," 1980
        - Layout design (Container 8)
  - United Nations Decade for Women Mid-Decade
    - Conference
      - Poster, 1980 (Container 10)
    - Subject files
      - Equal Rights Amendment
        - Poster, United Methodist Family Life Committee, 1978 (Container 14)
- Part II: Langston Hughes, 1925-2009 (Box II:1-8)
  Correspondence, poems, published and draft articles, photographs, research files, Federal Bureau of Investigation case files, books, newspaper and magazine clippings, and miscellaneous material related to Faith Berry's research for her biography of the poet Langston Hughes and for commemorative projects based on the life and works of the poet.
  - Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, 1972-1983 (Box II:1)
  - Bass, George Houston, 1978-1984
  - Biddle, Edmund Randolph, 1971-1987, 1971-1984
  - "Black and White," unproduced film, 1932-1935, 1964-1968, 1975, (2 folders)
  - Bontemps, Arna, 1970-1972
  - The Brownies' Book, 1970-1972
  - California, 1934-1941
  - Chicago Defender, Here to Yonder, column, 1942
  - Commemorative tributes and works by others based on his work
    - Langston, 1979
    - The Legacy of Langston Hughes
      - Consultants, 1981
      - Drafts, 1981, (2 folders)
      - Material used in documentary, 1981, (2 folders) (Box II:2)
      - Outlines, 1981
      - WETA, 1975-1981
    - Miscellaneous, 1968, 1975-1982, 1988-1992, 2002-2004, undated
  - Critiques of his work, 1926-1998, (5 folders)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Box II:3)
    - Case file, 1936-1965, (2 folders)
    - Correspondence, 1950, 19791-1981, 1950, 1971-1981; (2 folders)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 1972-1982, 1994
  - Fisk University, Special Collections, Nashville, Tenn., research trip, 1963, (2 folders)
  - Gallup, Donald, 1978
  - Good Morning, Revolution: Uncollected Social Protest Writings by Langston Hughes
    - First edition, 1973
    - Second edition, 1992, (2 folders)
  - Hughes, James N. (father), 1971 (Box II:4)
  - Joplin, Mo., 1976-1977
  - Langston Hughes: Before and Beyond Harlem, book covers, brochure, 1983
  - "Langston Hughes of Kansas," Kansas History, 1986, 1980
  - Langston Hughes Review
    - Hughes, Langston, commemorative issue
      - Bass, George H., 1987
      - Briere, J. F., 1987
      - Carrabino, Victor, 1987
      - Diaz-Diacoretz, Myriam, 1987
      - Fabre, Michel, 1987
      - Kennedy, Ellen Conroy, 1987
      - Kitamura, Takao, 1987
      - Lubin, Maurice, 1987
      - Miscellany, 1987
      - Morejon, Nancy, 1987
      - Rubeo, Ugo, 1987
      - Singh, Amritjit, 1987
    - Turner, Darwin T., commemorative issue
      - Biographical information, 1992
      - Correspondence and draft articles, 1992, (2 folders)
      - Errata, 1992 (Box II:5)
      - Turner, Jean (wife), correspondence, 1992
  - Langston Hughes Society, 1990, undated
  - Lecture tours and public appearances, 1959, 1967, 1982
  - Leyda, Si-Lan Chen, 1934-1946, 1977-1978
  - Lieber, Maxim, 1938, 1947-1951, 1978-1980, (2 folders)
  - Lincoln University, Chester, Pa., 1926-1929, 1940-1943, 1953, 1981-1984, 1992
  - Literary influences, 1935, 1950, 1992, 1994
  - Lynch, Hollis Ralph, 1969-1974
  - Mason, Charlotte Osgood, 1929-1930, 1939, undated
  - Mason, Charlotte Osgood, 1929-1930, 1939, undated (Box II:6)
  - Miscellany, 1955-1997, undated
  - Musical theatre, 1930-1992, undated, (3 folders)
  - Negro History Bulletin, 1950-1952
  - Newspaper clippings, 1977-1983, 1998-1999, undated
  - Nugent, Bruce, 1977
  - Obituaries, friends and associates, 1973-2009
  - Patterson, Louise Thompson, 1932, 1959, 1970-1971
  - Photographs
    - Hughes, Langston, childhood photographs; and his mother Carrie Langston Hughes (George Houston Bass, donor), undated
    - Hughes, Langston, Cornelius Lardner, and Thomas Fortune Fletcher at Fisk University (Johnnie Mae Newton Berry [Faith's mother], photographer), 1931
    - Hughes, Langston, Mercer Cook, Leopold Senghor, others (Mercer Cook, donor), undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1925-1926, undated See also Oversize
    - Patterson, Louise Thompson, Langston Hughes, others (Louise Thompson Patterson, donor), 1971 (Box II:7)
  - Posten, Ted, 1971
  - Rome, Harold, 1978
  - Roxborough, Elsie, 1971-1984
  - Rucker, Bernard, 1977
  - Scottsboro Limited, 1931-1937, 1973-1978
  - Seton, Marie, 1977
  - Short, John D., 1978-1979
  - Smithsonian Folkways Recordings, 1991-1995
  - Spanish Civil War, 1936-1938, 1949, 1968-1972, 1982
  - Spingarn, Amy Einstein, 1971
  - Thorpe, Francis Wills, 1971
  - Translator, 1948, 1957, 1968, undated
  - United States Senate Committee on Government Operations, testimony, 1952
  - Whitman, Walt, influence on Hughes, 1941-1946, 1953-1955, 1970, 1985, undated
  - Winter, Ella, 1978
  - Wirth, Thomas, 1927, 1983
  - Writers and writings, 1935-1939, 1949-1950, 1959-1965
  - Writings by Hughes, "The Bitter River" (poem), in The Black Nation, 1950-1952
  - Writings by Hughes from 1940s periodicals, 1940-1949
  - Writings by Hughes from 1950s periodicals, 1950-1959 (Box II:8)
- Part II: J. Saunders Redding, 1939-1991 (Box II:8-12)
  Published and draft articles by and about Redding, correspondence, pasteup book chapters, photographs, speeches, topical files, and miscellaneous material related to A Scholar's Conscience, an anthology of Redding's writings Berry edited.
  - Articles about Redding, 1939-1988 (Box II:8)
  - Articles by Redding, 1944-1950, 1956-1975, 1982-1986, (2 folders)
  - Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y.
    - Africana Studies and Research Center, 1969-1970
    - Miscellany, 1969-1974
  - Early fiction, 1923-1931, 1988-1989
  - George Washington University, Washington, D. C., 1969-1970
  - Hughes, Langston (Box II:9)
    - Berry, Faith, "Saunders Redding as Literary Critic of Langston Hughes," 1986
    - Book reviews by Redding, 1944-1963
  - Savery, Pancho, 1988
  - A Scholar's Conscience, book
    - Amended, deleted, or unused writings, 1942-1975, (6 folders)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1989
    - Correspondence, 1982-1989, (2 folders) (Box II:10)
    - Drafts, 1991
    - Drafts, undated
    - Drafts, final pasteup, circa 1991
    - Drafts, final pasteup, circa 1991, (2 folders) (Box II:11)
    - Index, 1991
    - Miscellany, 1991-1992, (2 folders)
  - Speeches and honorary degrees, 1967-1971
  - Speeches and honorary degrees, 1967-1971 (Box II:12)
  - United States Information Agency, including portrait photographs, 1962
- Part II: Miscellany, 1931-1999 (Box II:12-14)
  Files documenting Berry's consulting business and her employment at the National Gallery of Art and WETA, a public broadcasting station, topical files, and her published writings.
  - Berry, Theodore M., and Johnnie Mae N. Berry (Faith Berry's parents), 1931, 1973, 1998-1999 (Box II:12)
  - Black Resistance, 1974
  - Faith Berry and Associates
    - Calendar of events, proposal, 1980
    - Correspondence, 1980-1982
    - One America project, 1980
  - Gallery 1221, 1982
  - National Council of Negro Women, 1980
  - National Gallery of Art, 1972-1975, undated
  - National Gallery of Art, 1972-1975, undated (Box II:13)
  - National Writers Union
    - Academic Writers Project and other issues, 1988-1990, undated
    - Loose-leaf notebook, 1984-1987
  - New Dimensions, 1975
  - Washington Independent Writers, 1981
  - WETA
    - Corporation for Public Broadcasting fellowship
      - Miscellany, 1975-1978, undated
      - Trainee handbook, 1979
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box II:14)
    - Flaxman, Fred, memos, 1975-1977
    - Haley, Alex, and Roots, 1977
    - Mao Tse-Tung, obituary, 1976
    - Proposed programs, 1975-1977
    - Quarterly reports, 1975-1977
  - "World Literature," program series proposal, 1979-1980
  - Writings
    - 1963-1965
    - 1966
    - 1968-1965
- Part II: Oversize, 1933 (Box II:OV 1)
  Photographs.
  Arranged and described according to the series, boxes, and folder from which the items were removed.
  - Langston Hughes
    - Photographs
      - Miscellaneous
        - Hughes, Langston, with a child in the Soviet Union, 11 x 16 portrait, 1933 (Container II:6) (Box II:OV 1)
        - Hughes, Langston, on a beach with a German shepherd dog, 11 x 16 portrait, undated (Container II:6)